You are being watched.
The government has a secret system.
A machine that spies on you
every hour of every day.
I know because I built it.
I designed the machine to detect
acts of terror, but it sees everything.
Violent crimes involving
ordinary people.
People like you.
Crimes the government
considered irrelevant.
They wouldn't act,
so I decided I would.
But I needed a partner.
Someone with the skills to intervene.
Hunted by the authorities,
we work in secret.
You will never find us.
But victim or perpetrator,
if your number's up, we'll find you.
When you find that one person
who connects you to the world...
...you become someone different.
Someone better.
When that person is taken from you...
Wait for me.
...what do you become then?
Are you okay, mister?
What happened to you?
I think I quit my job.
Next stop, New Rochelle.
Morning, Finch.
You're off to an early start, Mr. Reese.
Maybe I'm trying to impress the boss.
You should have called first.
As it stands, our docket is clear.
We don't have a number?
- You sound disappointed.
- Oh, a little surprised.
No one in New York is in danger
or planning to hurt someone?
If they are,
they're keeping it to themselves.
Anyway, I think you've earned
some time off. Especially today.
Or did you think I didn't know?
Happy birthday.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Now go. Do whatever you do
when you're not here.
- You don't know what that is?
- I respect your privacy, John.
Obviously.
Cannon eight to six.
Horse two to three.
Ha-ha-ha. Are you sure?
You tell me, Han.
As I recall, John...
...you don't make any move
you're not sure of.
You're not working today?
My boss gave me the day off.
It's my birthday.
- Thank you.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Did you get any gifts?
One.
A key.
To what?
Good question.
Detective Carter.
Special Agent Donnelly.
How goes your hunt
for our mystery man?
That's why I'm here. I promised I'd keep
you in the loop on our investigation.
So we've been looking into
a smuggling ring that was broken up...
...a couple months back. The leader
was suspected of having CIA ties.
- He skipped before he could be charged.
- I recall.
Yeah, well, we think your guy
was working for him.
CSU found prints
and some carbonized blood...
...along with the body of a member of
the ring in the trunk of a car.
When they ran the blood,
they got a DNA hit...
...on a cold case up in New Rochelle
from 2011.
- What kind of cold case?
- Uh, suspected homicide.
Real-estate developer
named Peter Arndt.
- Real-estate developer?
- Arndt was up to his eyeballs in debt.
Lost his investors' money. We think one
of them had him taken out...
...and hired your guy to do the job.
And he made some mistakes.
Someone in New Rochelle has to know
something. And then we'll be close.
- Close to what?
- Finding out who this man really is.
Uh, well, um, thank you for the update.
- How'd you like to assist?
- Assist?
- Up in New Rochelle.
- Uh, I would love to, but...
You're the reason we're onto this guy.
You should be part of taking him down.
- I'll let you know.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
- Hello, detective.
There's something I need to discuss.
Yeah, I got something for you too.
Never pegged you
as the cues-and-brews type.
All the more reason to come here.
Once we become predictable,
we become vulnerable.
If you say so.
What can I get you?
- Uh, club soda for me. Thanks.
When I called,
you said you had something.
You know about a case
up in New Rochelle?
I'll take that as a yes.
FBI linked your partner's DNA
to a crime scene.
- Agent Donnelly, no doubt.
- He wants me along for the ride.
- Perhaps that wouldn't be a bad thing.
- How do you mean?
If there was any evidence
that threatened our friend...
...I'm confident you would find it
before Donnelly would.
Are you suggesting
I obstruct a federal investigation?
What you did with that evidence
would be entirely your concern.
You had to talk to me about something.
Oh, it was nothing important.
We'll talk again when you get back.
Thanks for the drink.
Anything else?
- I'll just take the check, please.
- Okay.
Here you go.
Thank you.
This is Jessica. You missed me.
Leave a message.
- Do you need any help?
- Yes, I'm, uh, looking for someone.
A nurse. Jessica Arndt.
I'm an old friend.
She might not work here anymore.
She was always talking
about moving away.
Um... Mm...
I'm sorry to have to tell you this.
Jessica died in a car accident.
About two months ago.
She said she would wait.
I'm so sorry.
I think I have her husband's number here
if you wanted to reach out.
Sorry.
- Has she left the apartment?
- Not yet.
- What's your interest in this broad?
- That's not your concern.
Just keep an eye out.
Karen Garner. She's wanted
for identity theft, passing bad checks.
Warrant's out. Your girl's a felon.
I'm aware of her apparent troubles
with the law, detective.
- I'm concerned she may be in danger.
- What makes you think that?
"Karen Garner" is an alias that's only
been around for three months.
She has no credit history,
only leaves to go to work.
- Constantly looking over her shoulder.
- She's hiding out.
Or on the run, more likely.
- Maybe she's trying to plan something.
- Yes, perhaps she's a master criminal.
But maybe she's a scared woman trying
to stay a step ahead of her abuser.
Yeah, right.
Let me ask you. Why am I planted here
instead of Wonder Boy?
Mr. Reese is otherwise engaged.
And you are not to contact him
regarding this matter.
You and I will handle this ourselves.
One out, bottom
of the fifth, it's Derek Mendler up next.
Mendler with a.233 batting average.
Six runs batted in.
Velasco with the pitch.
Fastball in there for called strike
and the count is nothing and one.
You can see Hernandez getting up
on that outside corner...
...and Velasco nails the location
at 93 miles per hour.
Detective Carter, welcome to New Rochelle.
Glad to see you took me up
on my offer.
Here's what we know.
Arndt was playing it fast and loose
with his investors' money.
He ended up losing it on bad land deals
and a gambling habit.
When he exhausted his credit,
he was forced to take money...
...from less reputable lenders.
- Loan sharks.
His bookie gave us the names
of a couple guys he introduced Arndt to.
- And we're checking them out.
- Says he was married.
- Wife deceased. What happened to her?
- Car accident.
Two months
before Arndt went missing.
Bad one. She was killed,
he nearly was.
Anyway, by that point,
Arndt was completely under water.
Shortly after he left the hospital,
he went missing.
They find a body?
No, but given the amount of blood
spilled, it's doubtful Arndt survived.
Doesn't sound like my guy's M.O.
He usually covers his tracks.
Another reason we think
it was his first job.
It was messy, violent.
Probably figured it would be easy then
found out he had a fight on his hands.
We located one of the loan sharks.
- You talk to the detectives?
- No, I had their files sent over.
- I'd like to speak with them.
- Sure. Let me know if you find anything.
Will do.
- Anything yet, detective?
- Yup, our girl's on her way to work.
And you're right.
Someone's got this girl spooked.
- How long am I gonna have to tail her?
- Long enough for me to identify...
...who she's hiding from.
- Hey, you see a woman come here?
- Yeah, she asked to use the bathroom.
Detective?
Hang on.
So if I were to speculate as to the reason
for your labored breathing...
- I lost her.
- That would be it.
- What do you want me to do?
- Go back to your day job.
I'll handle it from here.
- Hey, what can I get you?
- Oh...
Just some information.
I was here last night. I thought I saw
my neighbor working. Karen Garner?
- Yeah, that's right.
- I was passing by.
I thought I'd see if I could catch her.
Normally you would,
but she called out today.
Another time then.
I'm sure I'll see her around.
Excuse me.
I couldn't help overhear
your conversation at the bar.
- You're friends with Karen Garner?
- More of an acquaintance, actually.
Brad Jennings, U.S. Marshals Service.
Is Karen in some kind of trouble,
deputy?
Karen Garner, also known
as Sarah Atkins, is a wanted fugitive.
- I'm trying to locate her.
- Don't know how I can help.
I thought I heard you say
you were neighbors.
Yes. You did.
So maybe you could tell me
where you live, Mr?
- I'd prefer not to get involved.
- I'm not asking you to.
I'm just trying to get your address.
Now if you'd prefer, we can do this down
at the field office.
Hello, Harold.
Detective Stills, Organized Crime.
This guy you're talking to is my C.I.
He's a confidential informant?
And money launderer
for the late Don Moretti.
Hey, I've got some questions for him.
You were risking his cover
by even approaching him.
Let's go.
What did he want?
Just to ask me some questions.
Funny. I've got a few of those
for you too, Harold.
Am I to assume
that you were following me?
I think the bigger question is
are you working a case without me?
I feared with this case,
you had sensitivities.
- I thought it best to let you sit it out.
- What kind of sensitivities?
Her name, or at least her aliases...
...are Karen Garner and Sarah Atkins.
She has warrants
for identity theft and bad checks.
But I don't think
she's a potential perpetrator.
I believe she's on the run
from someone.
- Who?
- Likely someone she was close to.
When I was first building
the machine...
...I kept seeing the same numbers,
a week, a month, six months apart.
Usually women.
I thought it was a mistake. How could
anyone's life be repeatedly threatened?
And then I realized...
...they were living with the person
who would eventually kill them.
I've been working to uncover who she is.
It might help us identify the threat.
Send me her address, and we'll finish
discussing my sensitivities later.
Hello, Karen.
Or do you prefer Sarah?
- Who the hell are you?
- Someone who wants to help you.
You a cop?
No.
But I know you're running
from someone. Who is it?
Boyfriend? Ex-boyfriend? Husband?
- Husband.
- I'm gonna ask you one last time.
- Who are you?
- My name is John.
And I help people
out of tough situations.
What do you know
about my situation?
I know it was bad enough for you to
leave your home, your life, everything.
And I know you'll have to keep running,
Karen...
...if nobody stops him.
It's Sarah.
My name is Sarah.
What if I said you could stop running,
Sarah?
I'd say you don't know my husband.
Mr. Reese, I traced Karen's former alias,
Sarah Atkins...
...to a Chicago apartment.
Manager said she'd paid rent
using checks with a different name.
He's sending me one of them now.
Sarah Jennings.
Jennings, he's her husband.
He's the marshal.
- How did you know that?
- That's not important.
- What's important is we can help you.
- We?
I have a colleague who will watch
over you while I take care of things.
- We need you to stay here.
- What is it you're gonna do?
Make it so you don't have
to be afraid anymore.
- Everything we have on Peter Arndt.
- Thanks.
Did this look like a professional hit
to you?
It's hard to say. Don't get a lot
of contract killings up this way.
But this guy Arndt owed a lot of money
to some dangerous people.
And this?
Report from a car crash
Arndt and his wife were in. Single car.
Husband swerved to avoid a deer.
Wife was killed.
Hell of a thing. Guy survives a crash,
only to get taken out two months later.
- I gotta take this.
- Thank you.
No new messages.
To listen to saved messages, press 9.
It's me.
Jessica, I mean.
I don't even know
if you check this number.
Um, I need to talk.
Oh. You scared me.
Who were you calling?
Nobody.
That's funny. It sounded
like you were calling somebody.
Jessica Arndt. Pretty girl.
Dead on the scene.
Blunt-force head injury
from the rollover. No seat belt.
Do you still have her x-rays?
Arndt. Here we go.
In your report
you identified two previous fractures...
...a broken wrist and cracked rib.
- Mm-hm.
May I?
Is that a spiral fracture?
I suppose it is.
She'd get that
from having her wrist twisted hard.
- As opposed to falling on it, right?
- Come here.
You're hurting me.
One other thing.
You listed her cause of death...
...as blunt-force trauma to the head
and broken neck.
As I said.
Could someone suffer those injuries...
...if the car's front
and side airbags deployed?
Not likely, but a body is subjected
to extreme forces in a crash like that.
Is it possible she had these injuries
before the accident?
- You're hurting my arm.
- Get back here!
Oh, no, baby, baby, Jess.
Hey.
Detective, I don't know
what cases you're used to seeing...
...but up here, car crashes account
for most of my business.
Just because something's possible
doesn't mean it's probable.
Excuse me.
- Carter.
- Detective.
I'm heading to speak with Arndt's
family, his mother-in-law.
- See if she knew anything.
- Send me the address.
- I'll meet you there.
- All right, will do.
I'm watching Sarah's apartment
and I'm tracking the GPS on her phone.
I've also discovered new information
about her husband.
According to the Denver
public records database...
...Jennings was sued twice
for excessive use of force on the job.
Both cases were dismissed.
He falsified the warrants on Sarah.
Trumped up the charges to enlist
the entire U. S. Marshals Service...
...into helping him.
- That's why she can't stop running.
Only one way
to deal with guys like this.
Guys who hide who they really are
until they get home.
What will you do, Mr. Reese?
Show him what a real monster
looks like.
Detective... Uh, what was it, Stills?
Have a change of heart
about me questioning...?
Your fellow deputies know why you're
here?
Chasing your terrified wife?
If you come after her again,
I will kill you.
No one will be able
to protect you from me.
Do you understand?
Finch, we're gonna wanna move Sarah
to a safer location.
Agreed. And then maybe
you can explain the wisdom...
...of antagonizing an entire
law-enforcement agency.
Mr. Reese, we have a problem.
- Hi. Uh, one-way to New Haven, please.
- Sure, just need photo ID.
- Thank you.
Something wrong?
Stop right there.
Get down on the ground.
Karen Garner,
we have a warrant for your arrest.
Suspect in custody. Track 20.
- Yes, detective?
- I just heard on the radio...
...your girl got popped at the train station.
Picked her up on a marshals BOLO.
- Where is she now?
- Probably still there.
Cops will hold her
until marshals pick her up.
Thanks, detective.
We have to get to the train station.
We're too late.
Jennings picked her up.
With his cover blown, he can't take her
home through official channels.
He's gonna make her disappear, Finch.
We need to get to her.
I may have a way.
Government vehicles now have mobile
hotspots for Internet access, like this.
- That include marshal vehicles?
- Yes.
So I can get into their network.
The trick will be figuring out
which vehicle is Jennings'.
- That's him. West Side Highway.
- He's taking her out of the city.
- Get out.
- Excuse me?
Leave the laptop. Now, Harold.
And get out.
Your daughter was so beautiful.
Oh, thank you.
- Were you two close?
- Very. We spoke most every day.
So you said you had some questions
about Peter?
Uh, yes, ma'am.
Uh, prior to his disappearance...
...were you aware of your son-in-law's
financial difficulties?
No. Peter had a good job.
He was a good provider.
Based on our information, he owed
more than $3 million to various entities.
Well, Jessica once mentioned that
they were going through a rough patch...
...but that Peter
was turning things around.
That was just before the accident.
Excuse me.
When you said Jessica told you
they were going through a rough patch...
...was she talking about money
or her and Peter?
Oh, no, Jessica and Peter
had a good marriage.
I mean, they had problems
like any married couple, but...
Detective, see you a minute?
I just got a call that a guy in a suit
assaulted four deputy marshals...
...in their downtown office.
- What?
I'm heading there to follow up.
Mind wrapping up with the mother?
- It looks like a dead end.
- Sure.
- Carter.
- What's this about an incident...
...with four marshals?
- It's under control.
- Are you sure? Doesn't sound like it.
- Yes, detective.
So how's your New Rochelle
investigation going?
Donnelly hasn't found anything so far,
but I think I have.
Oh?
Yeah, I think Arndt killed his wife
and covered it up.
The kind of thing you guys
usually intervene in...
...except this time your partner
was too late.
Still don't understand John's
connection to this.
Sure there isn't anything
you can tell me?
I'm sure you'll make sense of it,
detective.
You were saying something about
problems between Jessica and Peter.
Oh, you know, just little spats.
Not even worth mentioning.
Do you know if these spats ever
went beyond words?
I'm not sure what you mean.
Did they become physical?
What is it you're suggesting?
Nothing. Just some routine questions.
I should get going.
I'm sorry for troubling you.
Peter had his faults.
But he loved Jessica.
And she loved him.
I'm sure she did, ma'am.
He was so much better
than her usual type.
She was seeing someone
before Peter?
She had a fling with a soldier.
Back when she was living in Tacoma.
This soldier,
do you remember his name?
No. They weren't together very long.
He was always away on duty
and then she'd be alone.
That wasn't the life for her.
He told her the same thing,
told her not to wait for him.
However sometimes I now wonder...
...if she had waited for him,
maybe things could have worked out.
Maybe she would be happy.
And we'd talk again.
Can I ask, do you have any pictures
of this man?
I don't.
But I still have some of Jessica's things.
You're welcome to look through them...
...if you like.
- Sure.
Jessica.
Oh, yeah, I got engaged.
His name's Peter.
That's one of the things
you learn over there.
In the end, we're all alone.
And no one's coming to save you.
Be happy with Peter.
You don't believe that.
Tell me to wait for you and...
Say those words and I will.
Listen, it's a party, okay?
Could you stop being so...
- Hey!
- Hey, cheers!
Listen, it's a party, okay?
Could you stop being...
In the end, we're all alone.
And no one's coming to save you.
Gene?
Hey, Joss Carter.
Good. Listen, I need a favor.
Personnel file. First name John.
Special Forces, stationed at Fort Lewis
between June and September of '01.
My eyes only.
Yeah, thanks, Gene.
Mr. Reese?
- What is it, Finch?
What exactly is your plan once you
catch up to Deputy Jennings?
To get Sarah away from him.
And Jennings?
Jennings had his chance.
He didn't take it.
I think under the circumstances it might
be good to bring police in on this one.
You hired me to take care
of these things.
You don't like how I do it,
hire someone else.
Mr. Reese?
John?
Carter.
- Hello, detective.
This New Rochelle business.
The car accident, the cover-up,
Jessica.
You knew what I'd find, didn't you?
- Knowing isn't always a blessing.
- True.
But I confess, I was calling with a more
John.
- Don't tell me you've lost him again.
- No, I know where he is, I just...
...can't reach him.
Or stop him.
Why are we here, Brad?
I wanted us to have some time together,
baby. Just you and me.
I don't know how things got
so out of hand with us.
But I promise, I'm gonna fix it.
You don't have to run anymore.
You believe me, right?
I do. I do believe you. I do...
So maybe we can take these off now?
You never did know what to say,
did you?
I know what you're thinking.
That this is my fault.
That somehow I wanted this.
But have you ever considered how hard
this has been for me?
The trouble I've gone to for you?
What's it gonna take, Sarah?
I love you so much.
But I can't do this anymore.
No.
Go.
- Where?
- Anywhere you want.
You're free.
Thank you.
Sarah.
She's gone. It's over.
- Something funny?
- You've never been in love, have you?
Really, truly in love.
- Why?
- Because then you'd know.
It'll never be over.
It is for you.
Your friend told me
I might find you up this way.
I can't let you take him, John.
This can't end like New Rochelle.
- Do I need to look in the trunk?
- You can do whatever you like.
Isn't gonna change what I have to do.
Let me have him, John.
- If I do, he'll get away with it.
- I'll see that he doesn't.
It won't be up to you. That's my point.
There are things you can do, detective,
and things you can't.
And that's where I come in.
I can't allow you
to just execute people.
This isn't on you.
It's on me.
All I'm asking for is your trust.
What, for you to do the right thing?
That I'll do what needs to be done.
Oh, yeah, Jess loves him.
Don't you, babe?
- Best move we ever made.
- That's right.
Did Sullivan send you?
Is this supposed to be
some kind of, uh, intimidation?
I don't have his money.
You don't have anything I want.
Not anymore.
Who the hell are you?
That's a good question.
Haven't known the answer
for a long time.
I know who I was.
I was the guy who left her behind.
You know why? The real reason?
Because I thought she deserved
someone better than me.
I thought she deserved someone
who would look after her.
Be there for her.
I thought she deserved
someone like you.
So I don't know.
I was hoping you could tell me.
Tell you what?
Who I'm supposed to be now.
Now that she's gone.
See...
...when you find that one person
who connects you to the world...
...you become someone different.
Someone better.
When that person is taken from you...
...what do you become then?
I was beginning to wonder when
I'd hear from you again.
I had some business to take care of
out of town.
I trust you now fully appreciate why
I couldn't tell you about Sarah's case.
I hope you now understand
why you should have.
Did you know?
Was she one of those numbers
that came up again and again?
What I know, Mr. Reese...
...is that New Rochelle happened
before we started working together.
Because of that, there was nothing
that either one of us could have done.
I forgot to include that
in your birthday present.
Must have slipped my mind.
- Hello?
- Detective Carter?
This is Warden Gustavo Pena.
- I'm calling from Torreón Penitentiary.
- Yes?
I have been asked to inform you
we have your fugitive in custody.
- My fugitive?
- Yes.
A Marshal Jennings
delivered him to us...
...along with 10 kilos of uncut heroin
found in his possession.
Uh, this marshal, just so I'm clear...
...was he tall, dark hair, in a suit?
- That's him.
He said you were
the original arresting officer...
...informed me to tell you
we have him in custody.
- He's going to be here for a long time.
- Thank you, warden.
One other thing. Do you have any other
Americans in your prison?
- One or two.
- Thanks.
I'm sorry to have to tell you this.
Jessica died in a car accident.
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.